Bang Dao

Vietnam daotranbang@gmail.com +84 9038191073

About Me

To me, building a new feature just like writing a new if statement with a new variable. So as long as the requirement is clear enough to know what is the condition of the if, the feature is doable.

I start with PHP first but now I'm mainly working on Django. I was be able to start working with python after **4** days self-learning then become leader assistant after **1 months**.

The most important things I learn from working with PHP is how the web work, what browser does, what server does and what can be done with the web.

Programming language, framework, template, etc... is just the things that expert build to solve the problem they met.

Technical Skills

Likes:

python, php, ajax, django, magento

Experience

Team Leader - East Agile

python django agile api

July 2013 - Current

I worked to build a general API for Home Depot which is used to build their web and mobile apps. We started with improving their test coverage from 30% to 90%, after that reduce the test running time from 10 mins to less than 120 secs. We have only 2 member on our side working night-shift with client in US for 9 months. The project end when client have enough member to handle this project in-house.

I start the job in East Agile with a project for Linqua. They want to re-build their ad system with good test suite. We built an ad server application (Python), an report system (Python) and rewrite some important part of their main application (PHP).

I got chance to work with some Javascript framework like AngularJS, ReactJS.

Team Leader - Vida

August 2012 - July 2013

php magento

I came to Vida to become their new team leader, the Magento team. The company give me 1 months to research, learn, and practice with Magento while looking for team members. There's not much people in Vietnam work with Magento at that time.

The team have 4 members at the time we have the first Magento project. We got more and more projects but the team size increase only 1 member to a 5 people size team, including me. Each 2 members handle 2 project in development phrase, 2 of them also in charge of maintenance that project when it go public. I was in charge of handle all most difficult part of those project including customize Magento behavior, writing new modules, packages, payment methods, etc... while teaching team to do so.

Our team is not the biggest team in the company at that time but we are the most friendly team or happy team in my point of view. We have enough time for 1 training class per week, my team members listen to me even all of them are older than me (I was about 24 at that time).

I learn and practice Git in this company, and after 2 year I realized I did a really really bad git process here.

Software Engineer - gloops Vietnam Co.,Ltd.

python django

I was a PHP expert when I join this company, my best friend invite me to join with her so that we can work together. The company was formed 2 month after the interviewing. I only know they were looking for Python engineer on first day of work. The company give each of engineer (it's seem no body know Python Django at that time in Ho Chi Minh city) 1 weeks to learn Python and Django. After 4 days of learning, I start with the first task of maintenance a project name "Legend Cards" game, the very famous web games in Japan at that time. After 1 month, I was given the leader assistant position.

We used Django to build web game application here. In 9 month, I worked with 4 game projects, fix a lot of bugs including 6 security bug that I found and raised. 2 of 4 project are the mobile web game.

The company try to use 1 general solution to build game application on both iOS and Android. I was given the task to research about all the technology can be used for that. Thus I touch iOS object-c, Android java, PhoneGap, Appcelerator..., build a game application for each of them as demo. At the end, the solution is develop 2 app, 1 for android and 1 or iOS for each game.

Tech Lead - Blueway Co. Ltd

October 2010 - November 2011

php zend-framework joomla prestashop

I start my own business with my friends at Blueway. I was in charged of building the engineer team, bidding projects, and control the quality of outcome. We developed 3 products at the same time, a web service, a self learning website, and a real learning tool for English.

The company was sold after 3 years.

This startup gave me a lot of experiences about managing a company, we have to care about the staff, the tax, the income, the company image, the people, the product, the vision...

Senior Developer - Vida

August 2010 - October 2010

php wordpress modx joomla

The first time I work in company office. I was a freelancer until I joined this company.

The company was forming, we started with some small projects like build websites base on PHP CMS like Wordpress, MODx and Joomla.

Build web Virtual Fitting Room allow customer to try new clothes on website.

I learned company manner here. Learned to use project management tools to manage the project. We used ClockingIT.

Education

B.S Computer Science - Dai hoc Quôc Gia Tp. Hô Chí Minh

2006 - 2011

software-engineering computer-science

Thesis 9.0 GPA: 3.14

Start my first job at the university's Software Experiment Lab in my 2nd year.

Start working as freelancer on 3rd year.

Join and build a charity group name Care and Share. Help to build their website and join their activity. Is member of organizer group of Challenge 2011

Projects

Stack Overflow

stackoverflow.com/users/414184

August 2010 - Current

Written 107 answers. Active in php, javascript, jquery and html.

GitHub - django-awesome-avatar

javascript django

github.com/squallcs12/django-awesome-avatar April 2014 - March 2015

Django Avatar field Support django 1.7 on python 3.4.3 Fix error on ratio is empty on saving fix error jQuery undefined by using django.jQuery

Native Content Marketing by Real Storytellers | Linqia

www.lingia.com

django tornado php api

Are you a brand looking for a scalable native content marketing solution? Are you an influencer with a reach of 10,000+? Find out how Linqia can help.

Build new ad server and report system. Rewrite some features on php application.

Home Improvement Made Easy with New Lower Prices | Improve & Repair django rest api unit-testing

www.homedepot.com

Shop online for all your home improvement needs: appliances, bathroom decorating ideas, kitchen remodeling, patio furniture, power tools, bbq grills, carpeting, lumber, concrete,...

Improve test coverage Reduct test running time Build API Refactor code

Citizens' Police Database

cpdb.co

django reactjs

CPDB

Build the website